list-manage1.com 2012-06-21

# Privacy | MailChimp

  1. Some Definitions 

The terms "we," "us," "MailChimp" and "Company" refer to The Rocket Science Group, LLC d/b/a MailChimp, a limited liability company organized and existing under the laws of the State of Georgia, or any successor or assignee of the Company. We are in the business of providing an online platform that our customers may use to create, send and manage emails (which, when sent using the "Services," as defined below, are referred to as "Emails" or "Email Campaigns"). The term "MailChimp" refers either to the business or the online platform as the context requires. The term "Services" refers to the services offered by MailChimp. The term "Member" refers to an individual or entity who or which is registered with us to use the Services. The term "you" refers to any Member (or other party whose contact information has been provided to us over the internet) who is reading this Privacy Policy, or on behalf of whom this policy is being read. The term "Website" refers to the website with the URL [http://www.mailchimp.com](http://www.mailchimp.com/). The term "Personal Information" means information about an individual who is a Member and includes any "Supplemental Personal Information," as defined in II.F., that we obtain. The term "Distribution List" means a list of email addresses of people that one of our Members has sent, or intends to send, Email Campaigns, and other information relating to such addressees, that we obtain, and includes any "Supplemental Customer Information," as defined in II.F. The information in Distribution Lists is sometimes referred to herein as "User Data."

MailChimp has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at our [Contact Form](http://www.mailchimp.com/contact) to email us. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint). The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, and does not cover information that may be collected through software downloaded from the site.

  2. Categories of Information We Collect 
    1. _Information You Provide to Us_ : When you register to use MailChimp on a free or other basis, communicate with customer service, or send us an email, you provide us with information that we collect. Such information may include your IP address, name, physical address, email address, phone number, cell phone number, credit card information, and other information such as gender, occupation and other demographic information. By providing us with this information, you consent to your information being collected, used, disclosed and stored by us in accordance with this Privacy Policy. 
    2. _List and Campaign Information_ : When you upload or create an email distribution list or put together an Email Campaign with MailChimp, we have access to the data on your list and the information in your campaign. 
    3. _Other Information We Receive and Store_ : When you register to use MailChimp, we store "cookies," which are strings of code, on your computer. We also use electronic images known as Web beacons. With those cookies, we are aware of and collect information concerning when you visit our Website, when you use MailChimp, your browser type and version, your operating system and platform and other similar information. With Web beacons, we can determine when you open email we send you, and collect other data. You may turn off all cookies that have been placed on your computer by following the instructions on your browser on how to block cookies that have been placed on your computer. However, if you block our cookies it will be more difficult, and maybe impossible, to use the Services. 
    4. _Tracking Our Emails to Our Customers_ : When we send emails to our own registered MailChimp customers, we'll sometimes track who opened the emails and who went so far as to click on any of the hyperlinks. We do this to measure the performance of our Email Campaigns, and to improve our offerings to specific customer segments. 
    5. _AIM Reports_ : Our Members who elect to receive AIM Reports, can also determine who has opened or not opened emails or clicked on links. That and all other tracking information available to our Members is also available to us and we may collect and review that information. 
    6. _Information From Other Sources_ : We may obtain additional information about you by using your email address, or other information, to directly, or through one or more services, search over the internet, or elsewhere. We thereby obtain information that appears to be related to such email address or other information, such as a name, age and participation in social media websites, (such information being referred to herein as "Supplemental Member Information"). 
  3. Use and Disclosure of Your Personal Information 

We will use and disclose your Personal Information only as follows: 

    1. **To promote use, including continued use, of our Services.** For example, if you leave your personal information when you visit our Website and do not sign up for any of the Services, we may send you one or more emails asking whether you wish to sign up. If you use any of our Services, and may benefit from using one or more other Services we offer, we may send you an email telling you about the other Service or Services. 
    2. **To bill and collect sums owed to us.** Uses for this purpose include sending you emails, invoices, receipts and notices of delinquency, to alert you if we need a different credit card number, and to otherwise try to collect money owed. We use third parties to handle secure credit card transaction processing and send billing information to such third parties, who maintain all information in confidence, to process your orders and credit card payments. To learn more about what steps we take to safeguard such data, see "V" below. 
    3. **To send you System Alert Messages** to let you know about temporary or permanent changes to our Services including planned outages, new features offered, version updates, point releases, major releases, abuse warnings, changes to our Privacy Policy and possibly other documents and agreements. 
    4. **To help enforce compliance with our Terms of Use and applicable law** including, but not limited to, helping to create white lists and black lists, to develop and test algorithms, heuristics and other methods and tools for detecting violations and to apply those methods and tools. For example, in this regard, although it's the Member's responsibility to make sure that the email address of anyone who opts out of receiving Emails from that Member is removed from all of that Member's Distribution Lists, we try to make that happen automatically. 
    5. **To provide customer support and obtain feedback.**
    6. **To protect the rights and safety of** us and our employees, Members, owners, officers and others 
    7. **To meet legal requirements** such as complying with court orders and valid subpoenas. 
    8. **To provide information received hereunder to representatives and advisors** such as attorneys and accountants to help us comply with legal and other requirements. 
    9. **To prosecute and defend** a court, arbitration or similar proceeding. 
    10. **To support and improve the Services we offer** including adding features and providing benchmarking and other comparison information regarding, for example, the relative success of a Members' Email Campaigns compared to other Email Campaigns by companies in the same or different industries. Benchmarking and similar information is derived from aggregating and analyzing data. 
    11. **To communicate with you concerning your account** for an informational, as opposed to promotional, purpose. 
    12. **To transfer your information** in the event of the sale of substantially all of the assets of our business to a third-party or in the event of a merger, consolidation or acquisition. However, in such event, any acquirer will be subject to our obligations under this Privacy Policy. 
    13. **To send you informational and promotional materials** that you elect ("opt-in") to receive. 
  4. Your Distribution Lists 

Your recipient lists are stored on a secure MailChimp server. We do not, under any circumstances, steal your lists, contact people on your lists, market to people on your lists, sell your lists, or share your lists with any other party, except as required by law or, regarding contacting, except in response to a complaint or other communication directly from an individual on one of your lists. Only carefully selected, authorized personnel have access to view Distribution Lists. We do not hold your lists hostage. We do not make it difficult for you to reclaim them. You may export (download) your lists from MailChimp at any time so long as we have a copy.

We will use and disclose the information in your Distribution Lists only for one or more of the following purposes: 

    1. ****To help enforce compliance with our Terms of Use and applicable law including, but not limited to, helping to create white lists and black lists, to develop and test algorithms, heuristics and other methods and tools for detecting violations, and to apply those methods and tools.
    2. **To bill and collect sums owed to us.**
    3. **To protect the rights and safety of** us and our employees, Members, owners, officers and others. 
    4. **To meet legal requirements** such as complying with court orders and valid subpoenas. 
    5. **To prosecute and defend** a court, arbitration or similar proceeding. 
    6. **To support and improve the services we offer** including adding features and providing benchmarking and other comparison information based on aggregating and analyzing data. 
    7. **To transfer your information** in the event of the sale of all, or substantially all, of the assets of our business to a third-party or in the event of a merger, consolidation or acquisition. However, in such event, any acquirer will be subject to our obligations under this Privacy Policy. 
    8. **To provide information received hereunder to representatives and advisors** such as attorneys and accountants to help us comply with legal and other requirements. 
    9. **To provide customer support and obtain feedback** about our Services, but only for and from the Member whose Personal Information and User Data are being used. 
  5. Safeguarding Your Information 

To protect your information, our credit card processing vendor uses the latest 128-bit Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology for secure transactions. In addition, our vendor is certified as compliant with card association security initiatives, such as the Visa Cardholder Information Security and Compliance (CISP), MasterCard® (SDP), and Discovery Information Security and Compliance (DISC).

MailChimp accounts require a username and password to log in. When you're finished using MailChimp, please click the "log out" link in the top right corner of your screen, to prevent someone from using your computer to access your account. You must keep your username and password secure and not disclose it to a third party.

Due to the sensitive nature of your Distribution Lists, we do not re-send forgotten passwords. Users must follow online instructions to reset their passwords if they forget them.

Account passwords are encrypted. We cannot see your passwords. We can only reset them.

  6. Notice of Breach of Security 

Nobody is safe from hackers these days. MailChimp will notify you, as soon as possible, if a breach in security results in an unauthorized intrusion into our system which materially affects you or people on your Distribution Lists, and will subsequently report the corrective action taken in response to the intrusion.

  7. Content of Email Campaigns 

When you send email marketing, it bounces around from server to server as it crosses the Internet. Along the way, server administrators can read what you send. Email was never built for confidential information. Never send anything in an email that you wouldn't put on a postcard. If you have something confidential to send, do not use MailChimp.

We sometimes review the content of the Email Campaigns of our Members to verify compliance with our Terms of Use. In this regard, we have software with algorithms to help us find email campaigns that may be in violation of our Terms of Use. We then have employees or independent contractors review those particular Email Campaigns. This practice benefits all Members who are in compliance with our Terms of Use because, among other things, it reduces SPAM being sent through our servers which helps to ensure high deliverability.

  8. Notification of Changes 

Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be posted to this Website and emailed to the last email address you have given to us, and will become effective as of the later of the date we post on the Website or, send the email. You may object to any changes within 20 days after they are posted on our Website or delivered to you, in which case none of the proposed changes will be effective with respect to information that we have already collected from you; but will apply only to information we collect or access from you in the future. There are purposes, other than marketing, for which we are not willing or able to treat information of any open account differently from that of any other open account. Therefore, if you object to changes in our Privacy Policy which relate to those purposes, we will have to terminate your account. In contrast, in the event we ever changed our Privacy Policy to allow us to have an expanded right to use or disclose Personal Information for marketing purposes, you would be able to opt out without any such termination.

  9. Accuracy of Data and Rights 

We do our best to keep your data accurate and up-to-date to the extent that you provide us with the information we require to do that. If your data changes (including, but not limited to, a change in your email address) then you are responsible for notifying us of those changes so that we can keep your records up-to-date.

We retain the data about you only so long as reasonably required to meet the purposes for which we have the right to use the information. In this regard, we keep some data, relating to when and where Emails were sent, which bounced, which resulted in a complaint and similar information indefinitely as we use such data to help us screen out violators of SPAM laws and for other permitted purposes set forth in III. above.

We will give you access to any of your Personal Information that we hold about you within 30 days of any request you make for such information. We may charge for providing this information to you, as permitted by applicable law.

  10. General 

We comply with the EU Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union. Details of our registration can be found here: [MailChimp's Safe Harbor Company Profile](http://safeharbor.export.gov/companyinfo.aspx?id=12701)

  11. UK Data Protection Notification 

We are notified as a "data controller" in respect of personal data about UK clients whom we collect personal data from in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Under UK law, we are a "data controller" in respect of the personal data about our UK Members but not in respect of personal data about people on your Distribution Lists (where we act as a "data processor"). We are notified with the UK Information Commissioner’s Office as a data controller in accordance with this Privacy Policy and our Registration Number is Z1907965.

  12. Effective Date 

This Privacy Policy is effective with respect to all data that we have collected, or collect, about and/or from you, both prior to your registration as a Member and/or during the Term, in accordance with the Terms of Use.

  13. Questions 

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns or wish to update, delete or change any Personal Information submitted on this Site, or have any questions about our Privacy Policy, please notify us through postal mail at:

MailChimp   
Privacy Department   
512 Means St., Suite 404   
Atlanta, Georgia 30318 

Or you can use our [Contact Form](http://www.mailchimp.com/contact) to email us.

Updated 08/24/2010
